

# Web Developer **Toronto**

# **ABOUT**

I'm a junior developer with a mind for creative problem solving and an eye for design. A recent grad of the Flatiron School in New York City, I have previous experience in environmental research. I'm excited to work with great people, and to use my diverse skills to make a difference through great code.

# CONTACT



s.andrew.reid@gmail.com



226.337.4243



sareid.github.io



github.com/sareid



linkedin.com/in/sandrewreid



## **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

Factbook of the Pacific ( $\underline{Demo}$ )( $\underline{Ember\ Front\ End}$ )( $\underline{Rails\ API}$ ) An Ember-Rails educational app serving information and statistics for small island countries in the Pacific

- Built fully-responsive Ember SPA with custom theme built in SASS using Zurb Foundation framework
- Built a Rails API serving country statistics in JSON using Active Model Serializer

 $\begin{array}{l} \textbf{Carrier Selector} \ (\underline{Demo}) (\underline{Github}) \\ A \ \textit{data analysis and visualisation excercise built in Rails, using on-time} \end{array}$ performance data for flights in the United States

- Used pgAdmin3 to parse and save million+ entry dataset to PostgreSQL database
- · Wrote custom methods and SQL queries to clean and manipulate data set
- Used D3, ChartJS, jQuery, AJAX, TableSorter and Bootstrap to visualise data through charts, maps and sortable tables.

### Janus (Demo) (Ember Front End) (Rails API)

An Ember-Rails app for keeping track of projects, tasks and bookmarks

- Used the Ember.js MVC framework along with Bootstrap to design a fully-responsive single-page application
- Incorporated custom drag and drop functionality using Ember components and HTML5
- Used ChartJS Data visualization tools to give insights into project progress

#### Edifi (Demo) (Github)

A social-marketplace where students can find teachers and sign up for oneon-one lessons in technical software

- Implemented Elasticsearch and jQuery to render real-time, predictive search
- Used moment.js to render dynamic calendar and scheduling
- Developed live chat feature using WebRTC, websockets, Pusher and Hark.js
- Incorporated user login from Facebook and Twitter with OAuth
- Used Ajax principles with custom Bootstrap theme to develop a single page application

# EDUCATION ———

#### Flatiron School, USA, 2016

Intensive web development accelerated learning program

# University of Waterloo, Canada, 2010

MA in Global Governance, concentration in global environmental policy

### University of St Andrews, UK, 2007

Joint Honours MA in English & International Relations

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **Ecologic Institute**

Berlin, Germany Researcher, Sept 2010- Sept 2015

- Developed and implemented communication strategies and products for EU funded environmental research projects
- Conducted policy research and analysis on topics including climate change adaptation, oil rig decommissioning
- Developed successful proposals and budgets for EU and German funded projects
- Awarded Konrad von Moltke Fellowship to support research mobility

## Permanent Mission of the Republic of Nauru to the UN

New York City, USA

Adviser, Apr 2009 - Nov 2009

- Provided representation and reporting to Naura as a delegate to UN meetings of General Assembly, ECOSOC, UNCLOS and more
- Drafted national reports, statements and briefings for the Ambassador of Nauru, as well as on behalf of other states in the Pacific on issues including climate change, security, and development

#### Centre for International Governance Innovation (CIGI)

Waterloo, Canada Balsillie Fellow, Sept 2008 - Dec 2009

- Awarded Fellowship to support MA in Global Governance
- Conducted research for the Centre for International Governance Innovation (CIGI) cataloguing climate change mitigation policy initiatives around the world

#### **ArcticNorth Consulting**

Guelph, Canada Guest Researcher, May 2008 - Sept 2008

- Contributing author on report assessing the vulnerability of the Canadian mining sector to the impacts of climate change, prepared for the David Suzuki Foundation.
- Conducted surveys of Canadian mining industry stakeholders on their perspectives on climate change impacts
- Compiled synthesis of project climate impacts across Canada under a variety of possible future scenarios

# **SKILLS**

Ruby & Ruby on Rails JavaScript, jQuery, D3, & Ember.JS HTML5, CSS3 & SASS SQLite & PostgresSQL Adobe Photoshop & InDesign

# **INTERESTS**







